Marlon Durand

P: 818-478-0657 | Durand marlon@yahoo.com| linkedin.com/in/marlon-durand-a7297a251/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Computer Science and Data Science major. Experienced in computer programming and data science with a focus on object-oriented programming, data visualization, dashboard building, data scrubbing, data analysis, and query building. Knowledge in hardware and software troubleshooting. An avid learner, problem solver, leader, and verbal communicator with experience in team building and critical thinking.

EDUCATION

LYON COLLEGE May, 2024

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

ELSIK HIGH SCHOOL June, 2020

High School Diploma

• **GPA:** 3.5

• Leadership: Track and Field Captain, AP Courses

COURSE WORK

Completed computer science courses: Discrete Math, Calculus 1, Introduction to Programming in C++, Data Structures with C++, Introduction to Digital Logic, Algorithms, Programming Languages, Operating Systems, Math Foundations for computer science, Numerical Analysis

Completed data science courses: Data Science Tools and Methods, Database Theories and applications, Data visualization, Advanced Data Science, Machine Learning, Calculus 2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C | C++ | Java | Swift | R | SQL | Bash | Basic

Operating Systems: Windows XP/Vista/7/8/10 | Mac OS

EXPERIENCE

Lyon College – Batesville, AR

Information Technology Services

Aug 2021 – Present

- Lead AV/Computer (projector, projector screen, tv, microphones, fenders) setup for +1,000 students and faculty
- Provide exceptional customer service to faculty, staff, and students through help desk and general troubleshooting support.
- Manage IT ticketing systems to track inbound customer support requests.
- Oversee PXE computers/laptops and pre-deployment and track inventory management of all devices at Lyon College.

LEADERSHIP

Tau Kappa Epsilon (TKE) Fraternity - Lyon College

Historian

Aug 2021 - Present

- Fundraising Chair
- Maintain a database of +400 alumni and +20 active members.
- Lead all written and verbal communication with alumni, active members, and National Headquarter executives
- Organize and lead monthly/yearly events to drive engagement of alumni and giving.
- Develop and organize charity fundraising events to increase local community involvement.

D.R.E.A.M Scholars

Member

Member

a. Our animation alordinated to attract and altraction activisms be already under

Aug 2020 - Present

Aug 2020 - Present

- Organization dedicated to students of diverse cultural backgrounds.
- Members awarded scholarships based on GPA and academic achievements.
- Lead mathematics and computer science study group to increase student success.

Track and Field

Development argains wealth argains askedular and athlatic appropriations

- Develop and organize weekly practice schedules and athletic competitions
- Champions of Character Award Recipient NAIA American Midwest Conference.